Guide to the Military Assistance Command, Vietnam Team 58 photograph collection, 1964-1965
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
- Series 2: Photos by Al Short, news articles (pages 27-51), 1964-1965
  - Subseries 2.6: Various Vietnamese military units, 1965
    - Captain Paul Yuracheck and Vietnamese children, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Captain Paul Yuracheck, Senior Advisor of the 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry regiment practicing Vietnamese with children while the Vietnamese Battalion Commander lies in a hammock.
    - Captain Paul Yuracheck with Vietnamese soldiers, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Captain Paul Yuracheck with the Vietnamese Battalion Commander and radio operator southwest of Vi Thanh.
    - Buddhist pagoda 1, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Buddhist pagoda (Kai Suu?) southwest of Vi Thanh.
    - Buddhist pagoda 2, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Buddhist pagoda 3, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Building near Buddhist pagoda (Kai Suu?) southwest of Vi Thanh; Battalion Commanding Officer without helmet.
    - PSYOP team and 31st Infantry regiment 1, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Provincial PSYOP team members working with 2nd Battalion 31st Infantry regiment southwest of Vi Thanh.
    - PSYOP Team and 31st Infantry Regiment 2, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - PSYOP Team and 31st Infantry Regiment 3, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - PSYOP Team and 31st Infantry Regiment 4, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - PSYOP Team, early-mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Provincial PSYOP team members embarked in landing craft enroute to an operation with Regional Forces/Popular Forces.
    - Captain James Degan 1, mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Captain James Degan, Regional Forces advisor, on operation in the vicinity of Vi Thanh.
    - Captain James Degan 2, mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Captain James Degan, Regional Forces advisor, on operation in the vicinity of Vi Thanh crossing a small canal.
  - Subseries 2.7: Life in the MACV Team 58 compound, 1964-1965
    - MACV Team 58 Compound 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Room in a "long house" on the MACV Advisory Team 58 Compound.
    - Sunday at the MACV Team 58 Compound 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Sunday afternoon get-together between the buildings.
    - Sunday at the MACV Team 58 Compound 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Sunday night barbeque with three team Non-Commissioned Officers doing the cooking
    - Sunday at the MACV Team 58 Compound 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Sunday "service" in the compound - Lieutenant Colonel Preston and two unidentified Non-Commissioned Officers
    - Sunday at the MACV Team 58 Compound 4, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Sunday afternoon sing along with Captain Eugene J. Wyles on guitar, Major Donald Gluck, Major Thomas LeVasseur, Jr, Captain John Coyne, Captain Stanley Bonta, Captain Clyde Meyers, and Lieutenant Colonel Preston.
    - Sunday at the MACV Team 58 Compound 5, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Mess hall meeting on a Sunday - Major Otis Moran, Major Donald Gluck, Major Thomas LeVasseur, Jr, and Captain Clyde Meyers
    - Al Short 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short in the "library," a corner of the mess hall.
    - 1st Lietenant Kevin Renahan and Vietnamese Children 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      1st Lieutenant Kevin Renahan and two Vietnamese children.
    - Captain John Coyne 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Portrait of Captain John Coyne.
    - Captain John Coyne 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Captain John Coyne 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Captain John Coyne 4, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Captain John Coyne reading mail from home.
    - Catholic orphanage, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Major Thomas J. LeVasseur with a Vietnamese interpreter presenting gifts to the Mother Superior at the Catholic orphanage.
    - Al Short 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short in the Chinese Park in the vicinity of the Province Chief's office, Vi Thanh.
    - Al Short 4, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      2nd Lieutenant Albert V. Short in the Chinese Park in the vicinity of the Province Chief's office, Vi Thanh.
    - Al Short 5, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      3rd Lieutenant Albert V. Short in the Chinese Park in the vicinity of the Province Chief's office, Vi Thanh.
    - Dinner with Choung Thien Province Chief, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Dinner hosted by Choung Thien Province Chief, Lieutenant Nguyen Ngoc Diep, with Major Otis A. Moran and Major Donald Gluck.
  - Subseries 2.8: Team members, 1964-1965
    - 1st Lieutenant Roland Johnson, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      1st Lieutenant Ronald Johnson in the team mess hall on a Sunday.
    - Captain Royal, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Captain Royal having coffee in the team mess hall on a Sunday.
    - 1st Lieutenant Eugene Gray, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      1st Lieutenant Eugene Gray in Team 58 mess hall in Vi Thanh.
    - Captain Clyde E. Meyers, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Captain Clyde E. Meyers and Sargent Van Corbach surveying the "new" Vi Thanh airfield.
    - Captain Thomas, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Captain Thomas of the US Air Force.
    - Captain James Degan 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Captain James Degan taking a smoke break.
    - Military advisors and Vietnamese officials 4, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Captain John Coyne, Captain Loi (Vietnamese Provincial Intelligence Officer), and Major Thomas J. Levasseur, Jr. at the Brigade HQ map.
    - Military advisors and Vietnamese officials 5, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      US light weapons infantry Non-Commissioned Officer and his Vietnamese counterpart drinking beer in a Vi Thanh restauraunt.
  - Subseries 2.9: Awards ceremony, 1964-1965
    - Award ceremony 1, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Major Otis A. Moran presenting the Combat Infantryman's Badge to 1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short. Also pictured are Captain John Coyne, Sergeants Spearman and Creamer, Captain Royal, and Captain Clyde E. Meyers.
    - Award ceremony 2, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Major Otis A. Moran presenting the Combat Infantryman's Badge to 1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short. Lieutenant Colonel Diep, the province chief, is in the background.
    - Award ceremony 3, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Lietenant Colonel Diep, Province Chief, congratulates 1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short on award of Combat Infantryman's Badge. Also pictured are Captain John Coyne and Sergeants Spearman and Creamer.
    - Award ceremony 4, late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      Lietenant Colonel Diep, Province Chief, congratulates 1st Lieutenant Albert V. Short on award of Combat Infantryman's Badge. A team administrative Non-Commissioned Officer and Vietnamese National Police guards are also pictured.
  - Subseries 2.10: News articles, 1965
    - Record American, Boston article, "Mekong Delta crucial in Viet War", January 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Boston Advertiser article, "Our New England Boys in Vietnam", late 1964/mid 1965 (Box 1, Folder 51)